grangehotels.com 2016-03-30

# Privacy Policy and Cookies - Grange Hotels London - Best London Hotels

## Privacy Policy

You authorise us to use, store or otherwise process any personal information, including but not limited to your name and address, which personally identifies you ("Personal Information") to enable us, our affiliates, our partners, successors (including the purchaser of the whole or part of our business), associates, sub-contractors or other third parties (together our "Partner Companies") to provide services and products which are available through the Website.

We agree that, as regards the use of any personal data, as defined in the Act, we will comply with the provisions of the Act insofar as they applicable to you.

We may use the Personal Information to send you information about new products and services which we think may be of interest to you, unless you opt out by contacting us as described at the end of this Privacy Policy.

If you would like us to pass on your Personal Information to our Partner Companies so that they may contact you with details of products and services which may interest you, please contact us in the manner set out at the end of this Privacy Policy. Please be aware that Partner Companies may be located in countries outside the EEA which do not have laws to protect your information.

If, in the course of you using the services on the Website, you provide us with Personal Information which relates to your racial or ethnic origin or opinions, religion or other beliefs of a similar nature ("Sensitive Data") We will not disclose this Sensitive Data to any person for any reason without your express prior consent

We may transfer or disclose Personal Information, to our professional advisers and to such other parties as We consider necessary, for the administration of the Website and related business or if required to disclose such information by law.

We may aggregate statistics, responses to any surveys and questionnaires, traffic patterns and related site information and disclose such aggregate data to third parties for marketing, advertising or other promotional purposes but such aggregate data will not include any Personal Information. To enable us to monitor and improve our Website, we gather and record on our servers certain aggregated information about you when you use it, including without limitation, details of your operating system, browser version, domain name and IP address, the URL you came from and go to and the parts of our Website you visit. Such information is primarily used to provide you with an enhanced on-line experience.

We use cookies (small files which are stored on your hard drive by our browser) to monitor your use of the Website during the time you access it. However we do not use the information these cookies collect at any point after you have stopped accessing the Website.

You must at all times ensure that the Personal Information you provide is accurate and complete and all registration details (where applicable) shall contain your real name, address and other requested details. You will notify us of any changes to these as soon as you are able so that we can update our records.

You are solely responsible for your Personal Information and we may take any action with respect to your Personal Information we deem necessary or appropriate if we believe it may cause us to suffer any loss, liability or commercial damage.

Any information provided by you in connection with any transaction regarding your credit or debit card numbers, expiry date and billing or delivery address will be used by us, or by others on our behalf, to process the transaction. These details will be stored on a secure server and encrypted and may be used by us to facilitate and personalise future transactions with you.

Whilst we will take all reasonable steps to protect your Personal Information, we cannot guarantee the security of any Personal Information you disclose online. You accept the inherent security implications of dealing on-line over the Internet and will not hold us responsible for any breach of security unless we have been negligent and then only to the limits set out in the terms and conditions for this Website.

You can opt out of receiving communications from us or ask us or any member of the Grange Hotels group by sending an e-mail to [support@grangehotels.com]

## Use of Cookies

### What is a cookie?

A cookie is a small file made up of letters and numbers that is downloaded onto a device when a person visits a website. These cookies are used to improve your experience, for example we will use the information to:

  * Recognise what you’ve added to the cart so we don’t have to ask again at the checkout
  * Provide a safe and secure service for online transactions
  * Measure how many people use our website to keep it running quickly and efficiently
  * Analyse how people use the site so we can make sure we provide the best possible service for our customers

Cookies cannot be used to:

  * Extract information from your device

### Types of cookies

There are a number of different types of cookies; session cookies, persistent cookies, first party cookies and third party cookies.

Session cookies – These cookies links your actions on a website to our data system and are used for a number of reasons such as remembering what you’ve added to the cart while browsing the site. The session cookies expire as soon as the browser is closed so no information is stored permanently.

Persistent cookies – These cookies remember your preferences or actions across a website and help us to provide you with information that is relevant to you in the future. The information collected can be used to track actions across multiple browser sessions and may be used to make advertising more relevant to you.

First party cookies - These cookies are set and handled directly by grangehotels.com, they cannot be accessed or read by any other website.

Third party cookies – These are cookies that we have given a separate website permission to use on grangehotels.com, these allow the separate website to record certain actions you take on the grange hotels website.

### What cookies does Grange Hotels use?

### Functional

Functional cookies are used across the site to make sure certain features work properly like the cart, checkout and custom content.

Specifically we use these to:

  * Remember the items you’ve ordered in your shopping cart
  * Remember the search options(dates, number of rooms, occupancy) so you don’t have to enter them for every search
  * Remember who is logged in when amending/cancelling bookings or making corporate bookings

We do not use these to:

  * Advertise products or services to you

#### Cookie List

  * session
  * cart
  * cw

### Analytical

Analytical cookies are used to measure site performance such as number of visitors, number of purchases and number of errors.

Specifically we use these to:

  * Gather anonymous statistics on how our website is used
  * Help us to identify and recreate any errors that may occur

We do not use these to:

  * Advertise products or services to you

#### Cookie List

  * __utma
  * __utmb
  * __utmc
  * __utmz
  * _ga
  * GALX
  * GAPS

## Other Cookies

Cookie name | Site | Purpose  
---|---|---  
  
guest_id  
original_referer

external_referer

| .twitter.com | These cookies are created by Twitter. In this case they are present because a Twitter widget or button is being used on the Grange hotels website.  
  
### How to control cookies

Altering your cookie settings is a relatively simple task however the process does differ between browsers. Here’s how to [access your cookie settings](http://aboutcookies.org/Default.aspx?page=1) in the most popular browsers.

### How to delete cookies

Deleting your cookie settings is also relatively easy but the process does differ between browsers. Here’s how to [delete cookies](http://aboutcookies.org/Default.aspx?page=2) in the most popular browsers.

You can find this and further information about cookies at [http://www.aboutcookies.org.](http://www.aboutcookies.org/)
